

MD NOOR E YAZDANI CHOWDHURY

Date of birth: 20/05/1996 Nationality: Bangladeshi

Gender: Male

CONTACT

Weiße Taube 11 44229 Dortmund, Germany (Home)



(+49) 017697718838

https://yazdaniportfolio.netlify.app/

https://github.com/Yazdani1

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ yazdani-chowdhury-650313110

ABOUT ME

I am a full-stack software developer (MERN Stack), Udemy, and Skillshare Instructor. I did my bachelor's in Software Engineering and currently, I am doing my Master's in Data Science at TU Dortmund University, Germany. I have worked in several international software companies where I have learned enough knowledge about software development and worked on several large-scale software.

I have been teaching programming, web development, mobile development, and UI/UX on Udemy and skillshare since 2018. I taught over 100k+ students on Udemy from around the world. I love to share my knowledge with others.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/04/2022 - 30/09/2022 - Berlin, Germany

Full-stack software developer

Berylls Group GmbH

I collaborated on the Trackwise SaaS application where I developed a frontend application using React js with Typescript, REST API, Chart.js, and Material UI. I did unit testing for the backend API using mocha and chai. I also used Storybook to document React component.

Company website: https://www.berylls.com/

01/05/2018 - CURRENT - United States

Udemy Instructor

Udemy: Online Courses · Self-employed

- Since May 2018 I have been teaching on Udemy. Over 100k+ Students are learning from my courses. I teach Software development and UI/UX
- Visit my udemy courses: https://www.udemy.com/user/yazdani- chowdhury/

01/05/2018 - CURRENT - United States

Skillshare Instructor

Skillshare · Self-employed

Visit my skillshare courses: https://www.skillshare.com/profile/Yazdani-Chowdhury/8145130

WORK EXPERIENCE CERTIFICATE

Berylls Group GmbH - Work Experience Certificate

https://drive.google.com/file/d/12bd9F_5EBHCzei_VwEzdU83_irLuPk_E/view? usp=sharing

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Language and Framework

Typescript, Javascript, React Js (React hooks, Context API, React functional components,), Redux-Toolkit, Bootstrap, REST API, Chart.js, Material UI, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Storybook.

Node js, Express Js, MongoDB, AWS S3, AWS SES.

Unit testing (Mocha and Chai), Jest, Git and Github, JIRA Board.

UI/UX Design (Figma and adobe xd), Cloud hosting (Vercel, Netlify, Heroku)

PROJECTS

Video-Streaming-Platform



Project Live Demo: https://video-streaming-platform.vercel.app/

Technologies/Tools I used in this project: MERN Stack, Typescript, React Js (React hooks, Context API, React functional components, Redux-Toolkit), Node js, Express Js, MongoDB, AWS S3, AWS SES, Git and Github, Bootstrap, REST API, HTML, CSS, Storybook, Vercel (Cloud hosting),

Project source code backend server on GitHub: http://bitly.ws/uFaz

Project source code Frontend on GitHub: http://bitly.ws/uFaE

Multi-user-portal

Project Live Demo: https://multi-user-portal.vercel.app/

Technologies/Tools I used in this project: MERN Stack, Typescript, React Js (React hooks, Context API, React functional components), Node js, Express Js, MongoDB, AWS S3, AWS SES, Git and Github, Bootstrap, REST API, HTML, CSS, Vercel (Cloud hosting).

Project source code backend server on GitHub: http://bitly.ws/uFaK

Project source code Frontend on GitHub: http://bitly.ws/uFaQ

Job Portal

Project Live Demo: https://mern-job-portal.herokuapp.com/

Technologies/Tools I used in this project: MERN Stack, Javascript, React Js (React hooks, Context API, React functional components), Node js, Express Js, MongoDB, Git and Github, Bootstrap, REST API, HTML, CSS, Heroku(Cloud hosting).

Single page company portfolio

Project Live Demo: https://react-company-profile.netlify.app/

Technologies/Tools I used in this project: Javascript, React Js (React hooks, Context API, React functional components), Node js, Express Js, MongoDB, Git and Github, Bootstrap, REST API, HTML, CSS, Netlify(Cloud hosting).

Project source code on GitHub: http://bitly.ws/uFba

Portfolio website

Project Live Demo: https://yazdani-portfolio.netlify.app/

Technologies/Tools I used in this project: Javascript, React Js (React hooks, Context API, React functional components), Git and Github, Bootstrap, REST API, HTML, CSS, Netlify(Cloud hosting).

Project source code on GitHub: http://bitly.ws/uFbz

Node JS API Unit Testing Using Mocha and Chai

Project source code on GitHub: http://bitly.ws/uFbh

Technologies/Tools I used in this project: Node js, Express Js, MongoDB, Git and Github, REST API, Unit Testing Mocha and Chai.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/09/2020 - CURRENT

Masters in Data Science

Tu Dortmund University

04/01/2015 - 18/12/2018

B.sc in Software Engineering

Daffodil International University

VISIT SOME OF MY UDEMY COURSES

React JS Responsive Single Page Company Portfolio Website

Course Link: https://www.udemy.com/course/react-js-responsive-single-page-company-portfolio-website/

Node JS API Unit Testing -Using Mocha Chai -Complete Project

Course Link: https://www.udemy.com/course/node-js-api-unit-testing-using-mocha-chai-complete-project/

React Responsive Portfolio Website - Complete React Project

Course Link: https://www.udemy.com/course/react-responsive-portfolio-website-complete-react-project/

Figma Mega Course - Design 6 Complete Web App UI/UX Project

Course Link: https://www.udemy.com/course/figma-uiux-design-a-complete-web-app-project-base/